Well, good morning again. Thanks so much for joining us. Real quick, I've got to do a clarification
for those watching online. I got a text earlier. These pants are not leather. I don't know
what's going on with the lighting and the live stream, but these are jeans just so we're
all on the same page. Okay. I am excited this morning, excited to be finishing up our series.
We've been three weeks on the verse Ephesians 2.10, which is kind of where our name is rooted
in. We are in this. It's Poema created for good works, which he prepared in advance for
us to do. And I wasn't here last week. Two weeks ago, Matt did a really good job of saying
to his few words, and he looked at me a couple times and said, that's right, I'll be wrong.
And then I wasn't here last week. I don't know if he noticed this or not, but he preached the
entire chapter last week. Did anybody else realize that? He preached the entire chapter.
So, if any of this is review, it's not my fault, Matt slid it in. I knew the love when I wasn't
here. No, I'm just kidding. Excited to finish up as we focus on this last part of Ephesians 2.
So, let's read it out loud, and then I'll pray and we'll hop into it.
So, for we are his canvas, created in Christ Jesus unto good works. Some say created anew in
Christ Jesus unto good works, which God has prepared in advance that we should walk in them.
Let's pray. Father, we're so thankful for this letter from Paul to the church of Ephesians,
encouraging them to live into all that you are calling them to be. We're thankful for this
specific text that gives us so much rich theology for our salvation, helps us to understand who we
are as individuals and as the church, and gives us a vision for our lives that is bigger than
ourselves. And we catch that vision this morning that we realize that the kingdom of God is so much
bigger than ourselves, but that we get to play a unique part in it. So, for your glory and for our
good. In Jesus' name I pray. Amen. Quick questions for you. I'll try out participation. Do me a favor.
Raise your hand if you like puzzles. Anybody like to do jigsaw puzzles? Keep your hand up really
quickly. Everybody look around. The people with their hands in the air are people that I will never be
friends with. You can put your hands down. You can put your hands down. I'm just kidding. That's
terrible. No, I really don't like jigsaw puzzles. I can't get into it for whatever reason. But
Mauritius's family, they're obsessed with it. We go on family, they taste them, and they do multiple
jigsaw puzzles. And any time we are down to them, they are doing these jigsaw puzzles, and I refuse to
participate. It's just like, I don't want to do it. I don't want to be a part of it. I don't like it.
What's the point? You put it together, and then what do you do with it at the end? You take it apart.
You put it back in the box. It's like, what are we doing, right? Not only are Mauritius's family
obsessed with puzzles, but my grandparents have recently really gotten into jigsaw puzzles. And the
cool thing about that for them is they'll actually get custom printed jigsaw puzzles with like
family pictures and stuff like that. And they'll put these puzzles together, and they'll frame the
puzzles, and they'll put it up. And it's cool because it's like pictures of the family. They
did it together. They got a friend. Like, I can get down with that. That's a little bit
more like meaningful. And so every once in a while, not because I like puzzles, but because
I'm a good grandchild, I will pretend to help with the jigsaw puzzle. I'll sit down with my
grandma and like, you know, shuffle the pieces around. But what I'm not doing is looking for
where the pieces go. I'm not going to go that far. I will put my hands on a couple of pieces.
pieces. And I remember the last time I did this pretending to help with the puzzle pieces with
my grandma. They got the entire thing done. They got the entire thing done. Except for
one piece. There was one, my mom's laughing because she remembers this story. There was one
piece missing, and we could not find this piece anywhere. We flipped the house upside down.
We moved roads. We moved houses. We looked everywhere for this piece. This is a custom piece, right?
Like you can't, we're gonna frame this, but you can't frame it with a piece missing. And so I
remember a couple weeks later, my grandma called me laughing like hysterically. She's doing
something around the house, and she's stuck her hand in her apron pocket. And the puzzle piece
had fallen into her apron pocket, and she was able to complete the puzzle and frame it and put
it up. And I tell this story because I think it's a helpful illustration for Paul's main
point at the end of Ephesians 2. So I think Paul is saying that collectively, as a group of
believers, we all have a job to play in creating this picture that God has designed for his church.
I would summarize my main point of this entire message this way. I would say that every believer
has a part to play in showing God off to the world. Every believer has a part to play in
showing God off to the world. Each of you got a puzzle piece from you came in, hopefully.
And if you didn't, then you're gonna miss out on a fun illustration that we're doing. But if you've
got these puzzle piece, you also got a uniquely colored crown. Did you know that Crayola makes
enough unique colored crowns that all of you can have a different crown? My illustration was really
going to fall apart if they didn't have that many crowns, but they do. So each of you, you've got a
unique crown. I feel bad for a person that got like brown. I'm sorry about that. Some of you might have
like metallic glitter. There's a lot of fun stuff going on. Radical red. And so throughout this message,
as I'm sharing, I'd invite you to just kind of, if you get bored, doodle color on that custom, or on that puzzle piece of that custom color.
So, and my goal is that at the end, we'll talk about it, but at the end, I hope that you have
that whole thing colored theme. As we think about this illustration that every believer has a part to play
in showing God off the world. Jesus 2 verse 10 says that God created us in the world of Christ Jesus so that we can do good things that he planned for us.
And I think the grammar here is important. Matt talked about it two weeks ago, but the grammar is plural.
It's written to the church at Ephesus. Paul is saying, all of you believers at Ephesus, you all have
good works that God has prepared and advanced for you to do. This is a plural idea. I would say that actually,
I think it has three parts. I think Paul, yes, he's writing specifically to the church at Ephesus,
but I think when he's writing to the church at Ephesus, he's thinking about the entire church all around.
He's saying that there is one bride of Christ, and the bride of Christ has good work that God has prepared
and advanced for them to do. And then I think you funnel that down, not only does the one bride of Christ
have good works that God prepared and advanced for them to do, but each local expression of that bride of Christ,
the church at Ephesus, the church at Rome, the church at Corinth, the church at Galatia, all of these churches,
the church in Winchester, we have good works which God prepared and advanced for us to do.
And I don't think it's too far of a stretch to take that down to the individual level. And so,
not only do we as the bride of Christ, every believer, and you have friends that are Methodist and Lutheran
and Catholic that would make themselves to the worship of Jesus, all of us have a part to play
in building God's kingdom. And then us in this building and in this community church, we have good works
that God prepared and advanced for us to do. But then, on the granular level, you as individuals,
you have good works which God prepared and advanced for you to do what only you can do. You have a
unique set of skills and experiences and circles of influence, and God has prepared good works for you to do.
So, we're going to spend the rest of our time focusing on the individual level, but I think it's
important that we put that in context. Yes, it's important that you and I figure out the good works
that God has prepared and advanced for us to do, but we should not do them apart from the context of
our church and without realizing that God is at work in his drive. Does that make sense?
I think far too often in the American church, we individualize our relationship with Jesus. And we
say, "Yeah, God's got good works for me to do, but I can do them apart from the church." I've talked to
so many Christians who have walked away from the church and said, "I haven't given up on Jesus,
I've just given up on the church." And that, that is disobedience. God has called us to do this
thing together. No, it's not perfect. Yes, we are a mess and we are filled with broken people,
but God has called us to do this thing together. You should not be doing your good works apart from
the church. God has called us to do that. And then what I think tends to happen too in the,
this is a show box. It's not really a part of the message, but I'm going to step one really quick,
and then get done. Thanks for your encouragement. I appreciate that. So, I think other local churches have
good works that God has prepared in advance for us to do. And what tends to happen is we tend to
gravitate towards churches that are doing things that we're passionate about, or we're excited about.
And then we look at other local churches in our city and in our community, and they're doing the
unique good works that God has called them to do. But we do this comparison game thing where we're like,
"Well, we're a really, we're a really good church. We're preaching the Bible verse by verse. We're teaching
God's Word. And those people, they do topical messages, and people eat it. They don't care
about God's Word. They're always, they're just trying to attract people into the building." And like,
and then we're like, "Well, we, we take care of the homeless through our church." And they're like,
"We care about, they do SPCA outreach, but it's something they're living." And those girls have
got more important animals. Like, we do this thing, right? Like, and I'm, I'm using really,
very examples, but we do this thing. Where we get into a church that we like, and that is a good thing,
but may we not be a church that looks outside our walls, in fact, judgment, at other local
expressions that are doing the good work that God prepared for them to do. May we join together
like puzzle pieces, building the kingdom of God in the city of Winchester with our unique
expressions of those good works. May that be our focus. All right, okay, I'm going to start that. Okay.
So, um, one of the first things that I hear when I talk to individual believers about the good
works that God has prepared for them to do is what I call the ministry. Excuse me. The ministry.
If you ever heard this on that, people will say, "Boy, you're, you're in ministry. You're a pastor.
You're supposed to do the good works, right?" And I'm just, I'm here. I come, and I put money in the plate,
and I, I come on a regular basis, and I'm here to encourage you and hear you. Oh, and I haven't
been called in the ministry. You've been called in the ministry. God has good works for you,
and I'm just a cheerleader. Anybody ever felt that way? Heard that said out loud? And I would
just say, you're wrong. Sorry. Actually, it's funny. Church leadership, ministry positions is
like the one thing that Christopher tends to come and talk people out of. It's like the Bible is like,
not many of you should be those people. Like, there's, there's way more things to do. Not
many of you should be those people. And then he gives a list of qualifications to kind of like rule
people out. I'm like, "No, no, no, no, no." It's because God has good works for all of us to do
specifically. If we were to use the puzzle analysis, possibly we're the most visible. We're on stage,
right? Worship leaders, the people that are up on stage. What's the most visible pieces in the puzzle?
Corners, right? The corner pieces. Like, I don't do puzzles. Remember, I'm bad at puzzles.
But when I do, do puzzles, I grab the corner pieces and the edge pieces. Eric, I did say doo-doo. Yes.
I knew somebody was going to get it. Sorry. But, but the edge pieces, the corner pieces, they're the
most obvious. They're the most visible, but they're also the most boring, right? They got the least
amount of color. And I think that I use that illustration because my good works are clearly
laid out in Ephesians 4. My good works are to equip you to do your good works. And so that's boring.
I mean, I love it, but for a lot of you, you're like, what? Like, it's where we get in the middle
where the colors start to explode and where you have really unique gifts and skills, and you get to,
you get to imagine what God might be doing in your life. I don't get to imagine that as much,
because my own thing is pretty laid out. The 50 things to do the work of ministry. Now,
there's some creativity in that. But, I should hear 50 say I'm not called to ministry, but every
believer has a part to play in showing God off to the world. If you are a follower of Jesus,
you have been called into ministry. You have a specific job to play in showing God off to the
world. 1 Peter 2 verse 9. But you are a chosen people, a royal priesthood, a holy nation. You have
got special possessions that you might declare the praise of the king who called you out of us and
sent into his wonderful rights. If you are a follower of Jesus, you have been called into ministry.
You have something unique to bring to the table, your unique personality, skill set,
spiritual gifts, circles of influence. We're going to talk about that more. That God has prepared
good works for you that you could lock in them. So, the first excuse I hear is the ministry excuse.
The second excuse that I hear from Christians when I'm talking about the good works that God has prepared.
They have been instillating this man. God doesn't want to use me. I'm too much of a mess up.
I messed up too many times. I've had too many opportunities and I've failed over and over and
over again. So many Christians, they want to stick themselves on the sidelines. They want to put
themselves on the bench because of their past failures and because of their fear of their future.
mistakes. And to those people, I would just respond to me, "Can you read your Bibles right
please?" And if you haven't, it's okay. Like, that's what I'm here for. I'm here to remind you that the
Bible is filled with people who messed up all the time. On repeat, over and over and over again. And God's
still supposed to use those people for his kingdom purposes. David was a murderer and an adulterer,
God called him a man after his own heart. Paul, who wrote a majority of the New Testament, was
murdering Christians. There was a demon-possessed man that Jesus healed. And the demon-possessed man is
like, "All right, now I need to follow you and learn about you." And Jesus is like, "Nope,
you're going to go do ministry." Immediately, right after being demon-possessed,
Jesus healed him and saved him to proclaim the gospel. Peter had his closest friend in the
eye of Christ three times. Jesus restored him and said, "You're going back to work. You're going to
feed my man." Shoot. On a small group, we have a running joke that there's actually, outside of
Jesus, there's one guy in the Bible who's like, they call him good. And it's Enoch. And he has one
verse, and it's like, "Enoch was good, so we took him up to heaven because we didn't need him."
Right? It's like, God doesn't need good people. He doesn't need people that feel confident and
equipped. He needs our brokenness. He's going to work through our brokenness. He's going to
read through us in Christ Jesus so that our good works flow out as who Jesus is and what he's doing
in us and not our own strengths and abilities. I love how Matt Damon says it. He says that God will
weaponize your weakness for his kingdom purposes. God wants to weaponize the thing that you're most
ashamed about. The thing that you're hiding from everyone else in the room. The thing that you just
can't seem to get over. The complacency that you just can't seem to overcome. God wants to use your
weakness. Let's recreate you in Christ and send you out to do good works. I love what Paul says.
Paul lays this out and says, "To me, as you hear this trustworthy sin that deserves full acceptance,
Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners by who I am the worst." Paul says, "God saved me
because I was the worst." He wanted to show to the rest of the world that there's not, you can't go too
far and outrun God's grace. For that reason, I would show mercy that in me the worst of sinners,
Christ Jesus might display his immense patience as an example for those who would believe in him and
receive eternal advice. If you're in here and you've felt that, that temptation comes back to you,
enemies seek to lie to you and tell you you've failed too many times. You've had too many opportunities.
God wants to use those in a unique way to build his kingdom in your circle of influence. If you're a
follower of God, you've been called into ministry. You have a unique part to play in what God is doing.
I don't care if you're broke, divorced, homeless, an alcoholic, a workaholic, a gossip, or any other
type of text collector or sinner, you pick your points and you fill in the blank with the thing that you
struggle with the most. God is not going to disqualify you because of your failure. He's going to use you in
spite of your brokenness. God wants to restore your brokenness for your good and for his glory.
Listen to how Paul says it in Galatians 2:20. He says, "I," so you could put on you there, "you have been
crucified. You're dead." If you have placed your faith in Christ in Jesus, you have died with Christ. And it's no longer your weakness that has power. It is Christ's victory through his resurrection that lives through you. And the life that you now live, you live in light of that resurrection power.
God wants to be crucified with Christ, God wants to use our weakness to build the kingdom.
Okay. Hopefully, by now, we've got that. We understand that there are, if you're a follower of Jesus in this thing, there are good works that God wants to do.
And if you're in here, you're not sure where you're at. With Jesus name, like, I hope that this is a, I hope that this is a blessing that you're grasping onto. I think so many people here are outside of the Christian faith. They look at the Christian faith as something that takes strength.
That makes their life more boring or more difficult. They have rules that they have to follow, and there's all of these things that God's, like, robbing them of joy.
But this is what the salvation of God is all about. It's about creating us new and giving us a purpose to not just serve ourselves, not just to be served, but to serve, to follow the example of Jesus.
And if you're here, you're living just for yourself, doesn't it get exhausting? Doesn't it get tiring to just live for yourself all the time?
We hear the key phrase all the time that it's better to give than to receive, but we don't live our lives like that. If you're outside of the faith, you'd probably often think about how you can benefit yourself in climbing your ladder and build your life.
You're alive. And it might seem like that's a better way to live in the moment, but you're not going to look back 30 years from now and say, man, I'm so glad I've been investing in myself, but it's awesome.
Salvation is not just about where you go when you die, but it's about what you do with your time, energy, and resources right now.
It's about what kingdom you're living for.
So hopefully we're reflecting with that. So what's the point of these good works?
If I dare you ever do them as a part to pray, no, what is this part? What are these good works? What should they be doing?
I know. What's the point of--we really have two good questions we start to tackle. What's the point of the good works, and how can I know what they are for me?
First, I'll say the point. The point is specific revelation.
Two weeks ago, Matt mentioned that this word koreema, that it is--only use one other place in the New Testament, in Romans chapter 1, and it's used with creation.
And in Romans chapter 1, what Paul is saying in creation is Paul is saying that creation is actually revealing to a watching world what God is like.
That God has intentionally created. That you see the sunset, and you see nature, and you see waves crashing on the ocean, and you see mountains and snow, and all of it is to display that God is powerful, incredibly created.
It's--it's generally revealing who God is, and what he's led to the Western world. That's step one of this masterpiece. We are step two. We build off of that general revelation, and we are there to proclaim specific revelation.
We have a relationship with God, and we are there to tell others how they can have a relationship with God, and what that relationship is like.
People can see in nature the beauty, the power, and the creativity of God that it is our job to take that abstract revelation and make it specific. Matt and his wife were at Yellowstone this summer.
I'm sure that you had conversations with people who were amazed by the incredible creation of God.
That incredible creation of God is not going to reveal to them how they can have a relationship with God.
Matt can take that knowledge, that information that they had about the awe and wonder, the beauty of creation.
You can say, "Let me tell you about the God who made all of that." That is what our good works are for.
Our good works are to take that step one of creation, God is beautiful and creative, and to declare to people that God wants a relationship with them.
I listen to this in God's podcast. It's weird. I'm aware of that.
But there's one guy, and they never talk about God. It's a God's podcast that never talks about God, which came to frustrating at times, but anyway.
There's one guy who has a hopeless face. All he ever talks about is when NASA takes pictures of the universe, and he's so close.
As he always talks about how small he feels in the immensity of the universe.
You know, it's God's masterpiece. It's his creation. It's created to frankly.
Right here. You're not alone. Your life is more important than just these few years that you have on earth.
But Jason can't get him to that point. He's making up all of these questions, but he needs a follower of Jesus to step in.
And to know that's the significance.
God is calling every follower of Jesus to good works that show a watching world that God is a God of righteousness, justice, grace, and love.
We help the world to see that God is a God who wants a relationship with them.
This is what these good works are all about. 2 Corinthians 5:40 says, "So we are Christ's ambassadors.
We are making his appeal. We speak for Christ when we plead come back to God."
So these good works are meant to display the character of God to a watching world.
And they will basically lead us to proclaim the gospel to a watching world.
So many of you are familiar with the quote attributed to St. Francis.
I hear questions kind of be fly by, like bombings of this quote all the time.
I really, I think it's a great quote, this quote in context.
"Preach the gospel at all times and when necessary you use words."
Esau McCauley, I think he builds off of that quote even more.
I love this quote.
He says, "Christian charity, good works, Christian charity is a recovery of the imitation of Christ's
ministry as human, as a sign of the coming kingdom.
It is done not to replace the need for teaching about the Christian faith.
It is another form of it."
This is what these good works are meant for.
They are another form of proclaiming the gospel to a watching world.
Yes, we preach the gospel with words, but we also preach the gospel with good works.
Our good works should include things like justice, justice for the unborn, for the abused, for
the sexually assaulted, for the immigrant, for the widow, for the orphan.
Notice how the good works that God has prepared in the business, they don't fit neatly into political
hierarchy.
God has not called us to be a part of political ideologies, of building political ideologies.
God has called us to build the kingdom of God, and the kingdom of God cares about all of those
things.
And so we have good works specifically meant to proclaim that with our actions and with
our words.
It involves responsible stewardship of God's creation, extending forgiveness to those who
don't deserve it, and just generally loving people the way that you would want to do it.
Christian faith isn't that difficult to understand.
Love God.
It's all your heart, soul, mind, and thinking, "Love your neighbor as yourself."
Every single believer has a unique part to play in showing God to the world.
So, now that we know that God has specific works prepared for each of us to do, and the purpose
of those works is to point people to the character of God, to help you to understand who God is
and what He's like.
Now how do we discover our specific works?
The reality is there's only one of you.
That's a line that I put in my notes, and I made it when I said it.
People would agree with it, but they wouldn't let it sink in.
Let's stop.
Like, let's let that sink in for a second.
You are unique.
God's created you on purpose for such a time as this.
He put you in your family, in your workplace, at your school, in your job, in your yoga house,
on purpose and for a reason.
And here's what I know as a preacher.
I've been preaching long enough to know that a lot of you hear that and you say, "Yeah,
yeah, yeah, I agree with it."
And like, let it sink in you.
I've created you on purpose for a reason.
You know, specific good works that He has prepared in advance for you to do.
He has given you unique skills, gifts, experiences, followers of Jesus.
You've been given a spiritual gift from the Holy Spirit to use for His kingdom purposes.
You have a circle of influence.
You know people that I will never know.
You know relationships with people that I'll never get to meet.
Your job is to discover ways in which you can demonstrate God's kingdom to them through good works.
I think you need the good works that God prepared for you.
You have to be the works that God has prepared for you.
I love how the ESV translate this.
It says, like I say the good works, "Why you should walk in them?"
And I think there's like this progressive idea.
Like step-by-step uncovering these unique good works that God has prepared.
I don't know why this always comes up.
They say be yourself and so God just keeps coming up, right?
But it always happens.
Well, it's an item maybe.
When I was in college, I loved golf, but I was too poor to play golf all the time.
Because it's expensive when college is expensive.
And so my buddies and I, we invented this thing more.
We thought it didn't invent it.
But we thought we invented it.
It's called kinkers golf.
These were yellow styrofoam balls that go about one-third the distance of a regular golf ball.
And we would take out a couple of irons.
And eventually, we got so excited about this that it evolved into me and my buddy.
We designed an entire 18-hole golf course that started from my dorm room, the front of my dorm room,
and ended at the back of my dorm room.
It's pretty elaborate stuff, right?
And I share this story because it evolved.
Like, we started.
We loved this thing.
We had this passion.
We had this thing that we wanted to do.
And we started where we were starting from, my dorm room.
And slowly and progressively, like, we just let the land show us where the hole was.
And we knew where we wanted to start.
And we knew where we wanted to end.
And then the rest was all up to just creativity.
And I'm saying that because I think that's what this process of discovering good works looks like for each of us.
It starts with who we are and where we are.
And it ends with where we know where we want to go.
We want to display the character of God to a watching world.
And so, from knowing where we're starting and knowing where we want to end, then we just personally ask the Holy Spirit to reveal us the ways in which we might display God to a watching world.
I think there's two elements.
It needs good works.
There's daily good works.
And then there's seasons of good works.
Daily, I'm, can I be honest with you?
I'm not sure what you said.
I'm going to say yes anyway.
You guys know how this works.
You know how this works.
I'm really bad at this daily good work thing.
Cause I have an agenda.
I have a schedule.
I have things that I feel like I need to accomplish in that day.
And if something gets in the way of accomplishing those things, I get frustrated.
I mean, but what if, what if God put somebody in your path tomorrow?
That he's out to you to do good work for.
That he has prepared from, before the foundations of creation.
He has made this thing happen where this person is going to cross your path.
And you're so busy and so focused on your schedule and the things that you have to get accomplished.
That you miss an opportunity that God has prepared for you to demonstrate his kingdom to this person.
This is the thing that I think that God needs you to focus on in the most daily waking up and saying,
"God, what is it that you might have for me to do today?"
May we do that.
May we wake up, spend time with God, and ask that question.
What is it that you do today?
May we do today?
And the second is, it's seasonal.
What are we going to give our lives to?
What are you going to give your teens years to?
What are you going to give your 20s, your 30s, your 40s, your 50s, your retirement to?
I think that God has intentional ministry opportunities for each of our,
one of those unique areas of ministry that God is calling you to serve on.
Again, this season of your life.
Intentional about seeking those things.
God, I felt called into church ministry at 16.
And there was a long process of prayer and exploration and asking people and discerning and trusting and trying.
And I still to this day feel called to ministry.
I want to be open to the Holy Spirit, directing me in a different direction.
Each season of each time.
And so, maybe you're here and you just email them yourself who God's calling you to be.
You have a specific ministry and you know how you can serve God.
And I'm just here to say great job and keep it up.
And maybe you're here and you're like, you know what?
I've never really thought about me being called into ministry.
I don't know what that looks like.
I volunteer at the church when people say they need volunteers.
But like, I don't know what my calling is.
I don't know what my specific ministry is.
How can I discern these good works that God might be following into?
I've got five things for you.
And they're in general.
I know.
And so, it's going to, you know, take some time.
But, these are the things that I would ask you to think about, to focus on.
Number one is your personality.
What are you good at?
What do you like to do?
Who do you like to spend time with?
Where has God placed you in your life?
It seems like something small and insignificant, but it's not.
Again, God created you on purpose.
For a purpose.
He placed you where you're at.
Intentionally.
For a reason.
How might your personality, the things that you like to do, your passions,
how might that lead into the specific ministry that God is calling you to?
Number two is opportunities.
Where do you go to church?
Where do you live, work, and play?
What physical and spiritual needs exist in your community that you might be able to do?
We all have unique opportunities.
Our community has unique.
And so often, I think, I think what happens is we get so reactionary.
We just do the next thing that needs to be done without really stepping back and asking God,
what do you have for me to do?
And I wonder if we don't actually get in the way and do other people's good works.
Because we're just being reactionary.
What opportunities do you have?
What opportunities does our community have?
How can we as individuals meet those needs?
And how can we as a local church meet those needs?
Three, it's perfect gifts.
The Holy Spirit has gifted you.
And what is that the Holy Spirit hasn't gifted me?
Discover those spiritual gifts.
Speak out an understanding of what they are and how God might be.
Why did God give you those gifts?
You specifically.
What is He going to empower you to do?
Number four, listening prayer.
For my doctors and Presbyterian sons in the room, this one's difficult.
We like to talk prayer.
We don't like to listen to the uncomfortable.
I speak from experience.
May we learn to pray and intentionally listen to what I might have to say today.
God, what time is He calling me to?
What good work do you have for me to do?
And as we input all of those things.
May we finally and lastly speak godly advice.
As we discover and spend time honestly speaking out what those things are.
Go to somebody who sucks.
Somebody that loves the Lord.
I feel like.
I feel like doing some things that I'm good at.
I feel like there's a need that I can meet in our community.
What do you think?
Do you think I'd be good at that?
Do you think I'm going to accomplish something bigger than myself?
Outside of myself?
And don't ask too many people.
Because.
And try that.
You might think and your friends might think that this is something that you're good at.
It might drain you so much.
Because it's not any good work.
Let's do this process together.
Again, remember it's in the context of our local church.
How can we create ministries based on our skill sets, gifts, passions, abilities.
Based on the needs of our community.
How can we build the kingdom of God uniquely?
What are our good works?
Good works.
A couple of.
A couple of fun of calls when it fails.
But don't do somebody else's good work.
Well, I talked about the demoniac earlier.
Jesus kills the guy.
And he says, I want to be your disciple.
I want to get in the boat and follow you.
I want to go where you go.
I want to do what you do.
That sounds like a real great thing, right?
Okay, Jesus says, nope, that's not for you to do.
I've got my disciples.
I need you to go back to the disciples, to the ten cities that you have unique influence over.
I need you to go do that good work.
If you just let him do a different good work, he would have missed out on his specific opportunity.
Maybe it's not your gifting.
It is your gifting, but it's somebody else's job to do it.
Second thought from the other day.
Just because it's not being done, doesn't mean you have to do it.
So many churches in America, a hundred percent of the work is being done by 20% of the people.
And you might hear that and you might think, yeah, I'm more than 20% and it's awesome.
No, it's not.
You're doing something you're not supposed to be doing.
You're taking your opportunity from somebody else to do the thing that God has called them to do.
But maybe they need you to not do it for a couple of months for them to realize that it's actually their good work to do.
So don't do everything.
Do the thing God's calling you to do.
Don't compare your good works to other people's good works.
Here's what tends to happen.
We tend to either overvalue our gifts and we get self-righteous and we're like, we're doing the real kingdom work here.
We're going to think of the ministry as a more important ministry.
And when you look at other people, we think, I wish they were going to help me because my thing is more important.
Or the other thing that we do is we self-deprecate.
Like, all I do is like bring up all speakers.
I always acted like he's on the stage.
Everybody sees the stages.
I mean, nobody sees me vacuuming up the kids at the cost of them, right?
Tell me.
It's good work that God has prepared.
He has prepared uniquely for the person that he's calling to do it.
And that's all the affirmation you need.
God has prepared it for you and you walk in obedience because of what he's done for you.
And that's it.
Don't compare yourself to other people.
Every believer has an individual part to play.
And like I said, it's both individual and in corporate.
We're coming together as individual puzzle pieces to create God's masterpiece.
He is using it to demonstrate his kingdom to a lost world.
His kingdom that has already come and it's to come one side of the side.
Right now, Dr. Tony Evans puts it.
It says, "Our job as members of the church is to live in a way that shows the world a clear picture of the kingdom."
And that all things fall underneath the Lord Jesus.
The church should present to the broader culture a working illustration of God's solutions to the problems the culture faces.
See those good works?
We're giving the kingdom of God to our city in a way that they need.
We're looking around at the needs of the community and we're presenting them with the solution of God's kingdom.
People who want to see heaven and work on earth should be able to discover it in the streets.
The church is to be the visible manifestation of the kingdom in history.
Every single believer has a part to pray and throw in God after the world.
The kingdom of God has come.
Jesus has established it through his resurrection, yet he invites us to be a part of it.
There's like this, this already-not-yet type of thing that's not going to be.
God has built his kingdom and he is building his kingdom and he is doing it through you and through you.
You guys have probably noticed these people coming up on stage and calling a picture.
Why are they doing that?
And why is Ronald just acting like it's normal?
Because it's weird.
It's not normal.
I suppose.
We have a picture here that's being colored.
It says color by number.
Anybody ever done color by number?
Color by number is fun, right?
It's a picture of a church underneath the cross.
And it's meant to resemble this already-not-yet thing that happens with these good words that God has proposed in it.
God is building his kingdom and the gates of hell will not prevail against it.
It will be a compliment.
With or without you or me.
He will do it.
But he invites us to be part of it.
He calls us to this unique good world.
It's like this color by number picture.
Barrett drew the pictures.
The picture is done.
It's already finished.
The colors have been laid out.
But we get to come up.
And we get to bring our unique expression to it.
We get to participate in the thing that God is doing every believer.
And the Clark's friend is throwing God off to the world.
If you're in here and not to follow Jesus, I hope that this, I give you this.
That's the vision of what salvation really is.
It's not just praying a prayer so that you can go somewhere when you're done.
It's submitting yourself to the authority of Jesus.
You know what's best for you better than you know what's best for you.
And if we would submit ourselves to the Lordship of Jesus, if you, person, maybe you're in here and you've never done that before.
Or maybe you've done that a long time ago and you've walked away and you've come back to this place where you're just living for yourself.
You're being invited and to participate in this incredible thing that God is doing for each and every one of us.
Don't waste your life on yourself.
Submit yourself to Jesus.
He has abundant life for you.
You're in here and you're following Jesus.
Unique good works that God has created for you.
You're in here and you're over the social security age.
Let me tell you this this morning.
You don't get to retire from good works.
I know you're tired.
I know life's been hard.
God has unique good works for you to do.
The kids in the self-pastroom that have submitted themselves to Jesus and been baptized.
They have good works that only they can do in their elementary life.
Parents, remind them of this.
Encourage them.
So we're going to take communion here in just a minute.
And on the communion tables, you're going to see empty silver plates.
As you take the bread and the juice, I invite you, if you're here and you say, you know what, I'm a follower of Jesus and I am going to submit this to Jesus.
I'm going to drop your puzzle piece in the prayer as a symbolic way of saying that you have prepared good works for me to do.
I acknowledge that I am your masterpiece created in Christ Jesus for unique good works that you have prepared and advanced for me.
I'm going to intentionally and regularly look for those opportunities to display your kingdom to a watching world.
Grab that puzzle piece in.
Grab your bread.
Grab your juice.
And it's an exchange, right?
It's like this is being built because of God's body broken and his blood spilled, but I have a piece to play in it.
And then jump your puzzle piece in it and keep your crown.
Put your crown somewhere that's going to remind you that you have a unique piece to play in this whole thing.
All right.
So, I'm going to attempt to give instructions for you.
I'll stop this out of the room and listen.
I think it's going to work.
All right.
Yes.
These people.
This session, you're going to come down this aisle, grab and go around.
You all, you're going to go this way to the back table.
You all to the front table this way.
You all to the back table this way.
You all front table this way.
You all back table that way.
You got it?
I think it's going to work.
Fingers crossed, friends.
Let me pray and I'll just miss you to grab your communion supplies.
God, we love you.
We believe what you say.
And you call us your name for peace.
We lead it through the dead boy of Christ, the broken body of Christ.
Confirmed through his resurrection.
We believe it.
And we acknowledge that we so often miss the good work that you created for us.
Or we do good work that you share with us with somebody else.
May we intentionally allow you to walk day by day in the light of your spirit, listening to what you might have for us to do.
And may you produce fruit through that.
God, may we see it.
May we see people responding to the gospel because of the good work that we're doing.
For your glory.
God, God.
He's missing my prayer.
Amen.
All right.
Remember the instructions.
Lead here on the front row.
Lead boldly.
Grab your communion and we will turn the service together.